What are you drawing over there?
A hypothetical containment field
for a frisbee-sized wormhole
that could serve as a portal to a parallel universe.
Oh, you silly doodlebug.
You know, a lot of scientists believe
that making contact with other life-forms
would probably not end well for us.
It's a frisbee-sized wormhole, Leonard.
You can block it with a Frisbee. Calm down.
Do you expect me to build this?
I expect you to wipe the pudding off your chin. Gentlemen.
Have you guys ever noticed that Sheldon
always disappears every day at 2:45?
Really?
He probably just goes to the bathroom.
Actually, no, he goes to the bathroom at 8:00 A.M.
With optional follow-ups at 1:45
and 7:10 on high-fiber Fridays.
It's sad that you know that.
Oh, that's just the tip of the sadness iceberg.
I'm looking at his public calendar.
2:45 to 3:05, nothing.
Yesterday, 2:45 to 3:05, nothing.
Last week, nothing.
Last month, nothing.
He never has anything booked during that time.
20 minutes a day, completely unaccounted for.
We should figure out where he goes.
Ooh, this is exciting.
Like one of my classic
murder mystery dinner parties.
Right, the case of who murdered
three Saturday nights of my life?
Colonel Koothrapali in the kitchen with the olive spread.
It was tapenade
and you guys suck.
So, how was work today?
Well, I spent most of the afternoon growing
isotopically pure crystals for neutrino detection.
That sounds like fun.
Yeah, it was.
Oh, good, I guessed right.
Who you talking to?
Oh, just this guy I met at school.
Oh, great. We're still dating, right?
Relax. He's just a friend.
We're doing an oral report together.
He's really nice.
I'm sorry, what was that?
I had a little stroke after "oral."
Would you stop?
Look, he just moved here from London, okay?
He doesn't really know anybody.
Oh, good, an English accent,
- the sexiest accent you can have. - No.
That's not true.
There's French, there's Italian.
No, you're right, it's the best.
Did you tell him you have a boyfriend?
It didn't come up.
Well, maybe you should tell him.
What am I supposed to say?
Say, "can't talk right now.
hanging with my boyfriend.
England sucks, you suck, USA number one."
Fine.
"Hanging with my boyfriend.
Talk to you later." Happy?
Yes. Thank you.
- What did he say? - Nothing.
What?
"Did your boyfriend make you type that?"
I hate this guy.
Don't be like that.
Come on, trust me, he's hitting on you.
No, he's not. We're just friends.
Look, is this gonna be a problem?
Because he's supposed to come over tomorrow to work.
Really? Here?
If it makes you uncomfortable, I'll switch partners,
even though the thing's due next week
and everyone already has a partner
and I'll probably end up failing the class.
That'd be great. Thank you.
2:44, right on schedule.
Hey, Sheldon.
Oh, hello.
Raj and I are heading over to the genetics lab
to pet the glow-in-the-dark bunny.
- Want to come with us? - No, thank you.
Are you sure? They turn off the lights,
and it's like a cute little laser show
that poops all over the place.
I'm quite sure. Good day.
Well, where are you going?
- Where are you going? - We just told you.
- I just told you. - No, you didn't.
Well, it's your word against mine; see you in court.
Should we follow him?
I don't know, I'm torn.
I want to know where he's going,
but now I kind of want to play with the bunny.
Hi, guys.
Hey, Alex, do you know where your boss just went?
No.
Don't you know his schedule?
All I know is corduroy makes too much noise
and I have to go find "quieter pants."
Come on.
Boy, what I wouldn't give
to get her out of those pants...
and into something a little more stylish.
This is where he goes?
What's in there?
I think it's an old storage room.
What could he be doing in there every day for 20 minutes?
Well, he's not doing 20-minute abs,
because if he were, he would have way better abs.
- Can you hear anything? - Not yet.
What are you doing?
I'm listening.
Can't you face the other way and listen?
I can't do anything right for you, can I?
What the hell is he up to?
He is kind of a weirdo.
Maybe he's got Leonard Nimoy chained up in there.
Or Bill Gates.
Or Stephen Hawking.
Why would he chain up Stephen Hawking?
Howard, please, you can't treat the man differently
just because he's disabled. That's not okay.
If you're wondering why
I've been staring through the peephole,
I'm trying to get a look at this guy
who's coming over to Penny's.
To be honest, I didn't know you were here.
It's not a big deal.
He's just in her history class.
They're working on a project together.
I don't even know why I care.
You know what, I don't care.
You think you don't care.
This is silly.
I have nothing to worry about.
Oh, I don't know.
Statistically speaking,
I'm sure you have something to worry about.
What do you mean?
Well, if we assume your looks are average,
right off the bat,
50% of men on Earth are more attractive than you.
That's 1.5 billion handsome lads standing by,
waiting to rain on your parade.
Well, yeah, but this isn't just about looks.
I'm way above average in a lot of other things.
Not height, vision, athleticism,
or ability to digest dairy products.
I'm talking about important things
like emotional maturity.
You were just spying on your girlfriend through a peephole.
I liked it better when you thought I wasn't here.
I'm not saying you don't have attractive qualities.
Your choice of friends is impeccable,
you're a good sleeper.
And last but not least,
you buy the grapes I like.
You're a real catch
compared to some snoring guy
with a fridge full of lousy grapes.
None of this matters.
I trust that Penny cares about me,
and nothing's gonna happen with this guy.
Well, unless of course he's a skilled hypnotist.
What?
While unlikely, it's still a statistical possibility.
She might be performing
sexual acts with him and not even know it.
Now you're just being ridiculous.
Am I?
The mind's a mysterious thing, Leonard.
He could be having the time of his life
while she thinks she's a chicken pecking for corn.
Look at us, sneaking around in the middle of the night
like a couple of cat burglars.
I think we're more like ninjas.
I don't want to be a ninja; I want to be a cat burglar.
Fine, I'll be a ninja, you be a cat burglar.
No, we both have to be the same thing.
Okay, we're ninjas.
Thank you.
But next time, we'll be cat burglars.
- It's locked. - Are you sure?
Yes, I'm sure.
Now, you stand guard, I'm going to...
It's locked.
Just keep an eye out.
I'll have this open in a minute.
When did you learn how to pick locks?
When I was starting to do magic in junior high,
I thought I could be an escape artist
like Harry Houdini.
How did that work out?
Pretty good.
I managed to escape friends, popularity,
and every party thrown in a 12-mile radius.
There. Ready?
- Hold on, hold on. - What?
Sheldon is a very smart man,
and he obviously wants to keep this a secret.
Yeah, so?
What if it's booby-trapped?
Don't worry, I'm one step ahead of him.
Great, what's your pl...
Are we good?
Yeah.
What the hell does that mean?
I don't know.
The solution to an equation?
Maybe.
It's a prime number.
Encryption systems are built on prime numbers.
What kind of secret does Sheldon have to encrypt?
He's always been very cagey about
what he puts in his egg salad to make it so tasty.
It's paprika.
Really?
Well, okay, one mystery solved.
Okay, good night.
Thanks, Cole.
- See you at school. - See you.
I'll be right back.
I thought you left a long time ago.
What's up?
You moving into the apartment on the fifth floor?
No, I was just visiting a friend.
Oh, cool.
That cute blonde on four?
Yeah. You know her?
I, well, I see her around.
I like to keep my distance
because her boyfriend is a pretty scary dude.
- Really? - Yeah.
He's ganged up.
She told me he's a scientist.
That's the name of his gang.
The Scientists.
They are crazy.
Well, thanks for the tip.
No problem, brother. Stay frosty.
We're still dating, right?
Oh, hello, Dr. Hofstadter.
Hey, Alex, and call me Leonard.
Dr. Hofstadter is my father.
And my mother.
And my sister.
And our cat.
Although, I'm pretty sure
Dr. Boots Hofstadter's degree was honorary.
May I join you, Leonard?
- Sure. - Thanks.
Hey, Alex, let me ask you something.
My girlfriend knows this guy at school.
He's got an English accent.
Ooh, I love English accents.
Yeah, you all do.
Anyway, I feel like he's hitting on her.
She says he's just being nice and that I should trust her.
It's probably harmless.
You know how it is.
I'm sure you get hit on all the time.
Right.
Because girls are always like,
"Ooh, that guy owns two Star Trek uniforms
"and gets a lot of ear infections.
I got to get me some of that."
I don't know,
I bet it happens more than you realize.
Trust me, it doesn't.
You sure?
You're cute, you're funny.
Maybe you're getting hit on, and you don't even know it.
Really?
I'm pretty sure
Okay, I got to get back to work.
Thanks for listening.
No problem.
Hope-hope no girls rip my clothes off on the way.
Come on, we're smart guys.
- We can figure this out. - Forty-three.
What is 43?
Besides my mom's neck size.
It's the atomic number for technetium.
That stuff's radioactive.
Do you think he's building a bomb?
It took him two years to put together
that Lego Death Star; I'm not worried.
Ooh, this could be something.
43 is the number of calories
in half a cup of fat-free yogurt.
Why would you know that?
I'm sorry.
We can't all eat whatever we want and still stay thin.
Wait, in the Hitchhikers Guide to the Galaxy,
isn't 43 the answer to the question
of life, the universe, and everything?
That's 42, dumb-ass.
Feelings.
We should stop.
- I'm exhausted. - Yeah, me, too.
We've got more important things to do.
Who cares what stupid 43 means?
- Not me. - Let's go home.
You want to get something to eat?
Sounds good.
What the balls is 43?!
I have to know!
Hey, shouldn't you be out with your gang,
spray painting equations on the side of buildings?
Come on, I'm sorry.
I just can't believe you don't trust me.
I do, of course I do.
Then why did you embarrass me in front of my friend,
who, by the way, knew exactly who you were?
- Really? - Your picture's on my refrigerator.
You know, I'm really starting to not like this guy.
What is your problem?
Do you use up all your thinking at work
and then have none left over for when you get home?
I don't know.
It's hard sometimes.
Everywhere you go,
guys hit on you, even if I'm standing right there.
And they're all taller than me.
Why is everyone taller than me?
You know what, this is all in my head.
It's my problem, not yours.
Leonard, why do you always do this?
Listen to me, you're the one I'm with.
You know I love you, so will you please relax
because you're driving me crazy.
You know that's the first time you ever said that you love me.
Yeah.
We're just supposed to pretend it's not a big deal?
That's...
exactly what we're gonna do because...
you're about to make me cry,
and we both know if I start crying,
you're gonna start crying.
- You're right, you should go. - All right.
She loves me.
"Hey, it's Alex.
Nice having coffee with you.
If you want to talk more, I'm always available.
Smiley face, smiley face."
What a friendly girl.
Okay, picture's up.
Looks like the camera's working.
That's good quality video.
It better be. It's the spare camera for the Mars rover.
How did you get your hands on that?
Million dollar camera--
ten dollar lock.
Oh, my God, here he comes.
This is it.
What the hell is that thing?
I don't know.
This is Dr. Sheldon Cooper.
Experimental log.
Wormhole generator test 44.
Wormhole generator test?
The first 43 parallel universes
I've checked proved to be empty.
I see no reason to suspect
universe number 44 will be any different.
Oh, my God!
Holy crap!
It's eating my face!
It's eating his face!
I found your Webcam and replaced the video feed.
You two should be ashamed of yourselves.
Sheldon, we're really sorry.
Yeah, really sorry.
Sorry?
You may not realize it,
but I have difficulty navigating certain aspects of daily life.
You know, understanding sarcasm,
feigning interest in others,
not talking about trains as much as I want to.
It's exhausting.
Which is why, for 20 minutes a day,
I like to go down to that room,
turn my mind off
and do what I need to do to recharge.
But what are you doing in there?
And what does 43 mean?
You don't need to know,
you don't deserve to know,
and you will never know.
Yeah, well I know how to make your egg salad now.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight...
Drat.
I'm never going to get to 43 again.
One, two, three, four...
Rats.